https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active

Skip to content
Google LLC
Active Participant
Other Covered Entities
See Purposes of Data Collection section for details on scope of cert
Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework: Active
Original Certification Date:
4/18/2017
Next Certification Due Date: 9/17/2021
Data Collected: HR, NON-HR
EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework: Active
Original Certification Date:
9/22/2016
Next Certification Due Date: 9/17/2021
Data Collected: HR, NON-HR
Purpose of Data Collection
This certification applies to Google LLC and its wholly-owned U.S. subsidiaries, it includes X (a division of Google LLC) and Chronicle LLC, but specifically excludes Google Fiber, Inc. and any other wholly-owned U.S. subsidiary of Google LLC to the extent of any current separate self-certification by such entity.
Personal data other than human resources data: Data is processed for various purposes depending on the particular product or service being provided, including: sales and marketing to consumers and businesses; supplying services and products to consumers and businesses; operating, developing and improving Google services and products; personalising Google services and products; financial processing and management; supplier, vendor and partner relationship management; fraud prevention, security, and protection of Google and our users; compliance with governmental, legislative and regulatory bodies; and customer support and relationship management. Data is disclosed to third parties as detailed in our Privacy Policy, including: in situations in which we have consent, for external processing, with domain administrators, and for legal reasons.
Human resources data: Data is processed for various employment and legal purposes, including: recruitment and staffing; compensation, benefit programs and payroll; performance management and training; compliance and risk management; workplace management; protection against injury, theft, legal liability, fraud and abuse; and other business purposes. Data is disclosed to third parties as detailed in our Privacy Policy, including for business-related and legal purposes.
As of July 16, 2020, we no longer rely on the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield to transfer EEA and UK personal information to the U.S. but continue to apply the Privacy Shield Principles to personal data we received from the EEA and UK in reliance on the Shield.
Privacy Policy
HR Data
Google Employee Privacy Policy
Description:
Describes how Google collects and uses employee data. Available to employees on Google internal sites and services. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for Google Employee Privacy Policy.
Effective Date: 2/1/2020
Non-HR Data
Document:
Alooma Privacy Policy
Description:
Explains the data that we collect and why we collect it, how we use that data, and the choices we offer to control that data. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for this Privacy Policy.
Effective Date: 1/31/2020
Document:
Elastifile Privacy Policy
Description:
Explains the data that we collect and why we collect it, how we use that data, and the choices we offer to control that data. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for this Privacy Policy.
Effective Date: 12/26/2019
Document:
Extended Workforce Privacy Privacy Policy
Description:
The Extended Workforce Privacy Policy explains the data that we collect and why we collect it, how we use that data, and the choices we offer to control that data. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for our extended workforce. The policy is accessible for each member of the extended workforce at the intranet and is emailed to them during the onboarding process.
Effective Date: 6/13/2019
Document:
Google Careers Privacy Policy
Description:
Explains the data that we collect and why we collect it, how we use that data, and the choices we offer to control that data. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for Google Careers Privacy Policy.
Effective Date: 2/1/2020
Document:
Google Privacy Policy
Description:
Explains the data that we collect and why we collect it, how we use that data, and the choices we offer to control that data. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for Google Privacy Policy.
Effective Date: 8/28/2020
Document:
Google Registry Privacy Policy
Description:
Explains the data that we collect and why we collect it, how we use that data, and the choices we offer to control that data. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for Google Registry Privacy Policy.
Effective Date: 1/30/2020
Document:
Kaggle Privacy Policy
Description:
Explains the data that we collect and why we collect it, how we use that data, and the choices we offer to control that data. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for the Kaggle Privacy Policy.
Effective Date: 9/14/2020
Document:
Looker Privacy Policy
Description:
Explains the data that we collect and why we collect it, how we use that data, and the choices we offer to control that data. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for the Chronicle Privacy Policy.
Effective Date: 6/17/2020
Document:
Privacy Policy for Nest Websites
Description:
Explains the data that we collect and why we collect it, how we use that data, and the choices we offer to control that data. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for the Nest Websites Privacy Policy.
Effective Date: 1/31/2020
Document:
Privacy Statement for Nest's Products and Services
Description:
Explains the data that we collect and why we collect it, how we use that data, and the choices we offer to control that data. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for the Nest Products and Services Privacy Statement.
Effective Date: 1/31/2020
Document:
Qwiklabs Privacy Policy
Description:
Explains the data that we collect and why we collect it, how we use that data, and the choices we offer to control that data. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for Qwiklabs Privacy and Privacy Shield Policy.
Effective Date: 1/31/2020
Document:
Workbench Privacy Policy
Description:
Explains the data that we collect and why we collect it, how we use that data, and the choices we offer to control that data. The EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs) serve as the dispute resolution provider for this Privacy Policy.
Effective Date: 1/31/2020
Verification Method
Self-Assessment
Dispute Resolution
Questions or Complaints?
If you have a question or complaint regarding the covered data, please contact Google LLC at:
Keith Enright Chief Privacy Officer
Google LLC
Google Data Protection Office
1600 Amphitheatre Parkway
Mountain View, California
94043
privacy-shield-google@google.com
Phone: (650) 253-0000
Fax: 650.618.1806
Privacy Shield organizations must respond within 45 days of receiving a complaint.
If you have not received a timely or satisfactory response from Google LLC to your question or complaint, please contact the independent recourse mechanism listed below
HR RECOURSE MECHANISM
Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC)
EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs)
NON-HR RECOURSE MECHANISM
Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC)
EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs)
Appropriate statutory body with jurisdiction to investigate any claims against Google LLC regarding possible unfair or deceptive practices and violations of laws or regulations covering privacy
Federal Trade Commission
